Hello
مرحبا
welcome back to our English listening practice.
مرحبا بعودتنا إلى ممارسة الاستماع إلى اللغة الإنجليزية.
How are you today?
كيف حالك اليوم؟
Do you feel your listening is improving now
هل تشعر أن استماعك يتحسن الآن
that you've turned off the subtitles
أنك أوقفت الترجمة
and listened carefully to me?
واستمع لي جيدا؟
Today's lesson is very important because
درس اليوم مهم جدا لأن
it's about visiting a pharmacy
الأمر يتعلق بزيارة صيدلية
a situation you might face when traveling.
موقف قد تواجهه أثناء السفر.
Let's start together.
لنبدأ معا.
But first, let me ask you a question.
لكن أولا، دعني أسألك سؤالا.
Have you ever visited a pharmacy in another country
هل سبق لك أن زرت صيدلية في دولة أخرى
and felt nervous?
وشعرت بالتوتر؟
Maybe you needed to explain your problem
ربما كنت بحاجة لشرح مشكلتك
but weren't sure what to say in English
لكنني لم أكن متأكدا مما أقول بالإنجليزية
or you wanted to understand whether the medicine is
أو أردت أن تفهم ما إذا كان الدواء هو
an antibiotic, a painkiller or something else?
مضاد حيوي، مسكن ألم، أم شيء آخر؟
In today's lesson, I want you to think
في درس اليوم، أريدك أن تفكر
what situations at the pharmacy
ما هي الحالات في الصيدلية
might make you feel confused or nervous.
قد يجعلك تشعر بالارتباك أو التوتر.
I will speak slowly and clearly
سأتحدث ببطء ووضوح
so you can follow easily.
لذا يمكنك المتابعة بسهولة.
Okay, let's go.
حسنا، لنذهب.